《シカマル : 逃がさねえぞ ゲンゴ！》
I won't let you get away…Gengo!
Dawn
To think, Shikamaru had
this many reinforcements
(サイ)シカマルが これだけの援軍を
待機させていたとはね。
waiting in the wings.
As expected of a coward like him.
臆病な彼には
お似合いってことかな。
I think you're misunderstanding something,
so I'm going to set you right.
(テマリ)勘違いしているようだから
教えてやるが→
We barged in on our own.
私らは勝手におしかけただけだ。
Shikamaru is hiding something.
((シカマルは何かを隠している。
Yes.
(我愛羅)ああ あいつが
独自に動くからには→
It must be serious,
for him to act alone.
よほどの事情があるはずだ。
Will you look into it, Temari?
調べてくれるか テマリ？
Use as much manpower as necessary.
必要なら 人手は
いくらでも使っていい。
Are you sure?
いいのか？
シカマルは 木ノ葉の忍だぞ。
Shikamaru is a Leaf shinobi.
Sand or Leaf… The age of
drawing lines is over.
砂だ 木ノ葉だという時代は
終わったんだ。
連合に必要な男のためなら
惜しくはない。
A man who is essential to
the Alliance is worth it.
Besides…
もっとも あの火影が→
I doubt the Hokage would
willingly give us intel.
素直に情報を渡すとは
思えないが。
聞き出すさ。
I'll drag it out of him.
I know you understand,
but do it as peacefully as possible.
わかっているだろうが
できるだけ平和的にだぞ。
ああ 平和的にやるさ
できるだけね。
Sure, I'll do it as peacefully…
as I can.
(カカシ)それで
これ以上 何が聞きたいの？
And…?
Is there something else
you needed to ask me?
(シカマルは 今…))
Shikamaru is now…
Anyway, we rushed over
(チョウジ)それで
シカマルのピンチを知った僕らは➡
after hearing that
Shikamaru was in trouble.
飛んできたってわけ。
Out of friendship, right?
友情ってやつかい？
泣かせるね。
That brings a tear to my eye.
Well, wait.
待ってろ 今から
嫌というほど泣かせてやる。
I'll make you cry so hard,
you'll hate it.
Leave Sai to me.
(いの)サイは私に任せて。
He's strong, you know.
あいつは強いぞ。
うん 知ってる。
Yeah, I know.
Sorry, Ino,
but you're no match for me.
悪いけど キミでは
相手にならないよ いの。
Let me take the old man!
あのおじさんは僕が。
(朧)ほう。
Oh?
Wind Scythe Jutsu!
カマイタチの術！
どりゃ～！
Wow, that was a surprise.
へえ 驚いた
でも２度目はない。
But you won't get me
a second time!
I shall show no mercy,
even if you are just a brat!
小童が相手でも
容赦はしないでござる。
Expansion Jutsu!
(チョウジ)倍化の術！
なんと！
What?!
Who did you just call a brat?
誰が小童だって？
鏃とかいったか
シカマルの隣にいるべきお前が→
Your name is Soku, right?
You should be supporting Shikamaru.
So, what the hell are you doing?!
いったいなんだ
そのざまは？
Like, I simply chose my master
(鏃)私はただ この力を
活かせる主を選んだだけだし。
in order to realize
my full potential.
なんだと？
What?
Like, staying under
a weakling like Shikamaru
シカマルみたいな
弱っちいやつの下にいたら→
is too tedious and futile!
窮屈でしかたないって意味だし！
Damn!
チッ！
今度は もっとよく狙うんだな。
Aim more carefully next time.
次に外せば お前の負けだ。
If you miss again…
you'll lose.
(ゲンゴ)貴君は必ず 私の志を
受け入れることになるのだよ。
You will definitely
accept my will, Shikamaru.
シカマル君。
てめえの頭は
どこまでも お花畑だな！
Your head's nothing
but a flower garden!
(ゲンゴ)諦めたまえ。
すでに手遅れなのだ。
Resign yourself…
It's all too late.
Too late?
手遅れだと？
いったい どういう意味だ？
What the hell do you mean?!
やるじゃないか。
Not bad!
でも 一頭を相手に
その息の上がりようじゃ→
But if you're already out of breath
against one opponent,
話にならないね。
you don't have a chance.
Sai, wake up!
サイ 目を覚まして！
僕より
自分の心配をしたらどうだい？
Why don't you worry
about yourself instead of me?
「自分がわからない」。
"I don't even know myself anymore…"
あんたが
最後に送ってよこした文に→
That's what you supposedly wrote
in the last missive you sent.
そう書いてあったそうよ。
I have the will that Lord Gengo
bestowed upon me.
僕には ゲンゴ様からいただいた
志がある。
だから もう
迷いなんかない。
So…I'm not lost anymore!
Oh…
あれ？ やりすぎちゃったかな？
Did I overdo it?
チャクラの反応がない。
His chakra's not reacting…
まさか死んじゃったんじゃ…。
No way… Did he die?
うぐっ！
対象となる相手に
チャクラの錯誤をもたらすのは→
You could say that making my target
misread chakra is my specialty.
拙者の得意とするところでござる。
何言ってるか… さっぱりだ。
I have no idea what you're saying…
シカマルも今頃 ゲンゴ様の前で
ひざまずいているでござるよ。
Shikamaru should be kneeling
before Lord Gengo about now.
Shikamaru would never…
シカマルが 屈したり…。
なんという馬鹿力!?
What brute strength!
するもんか～！
…bow down to anyone!
部分倍化の術。
Partial Expansion Jutsu!
おのれ…。
Why you—!
ぐわっ！
くらえ！
Take this!
チッ！
くっ…。
大カマイタチの術！
Cyclone Scythe Jutsu!
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
I'll never give up...
大切な仲間のために
私は絶対 諦めない。
on a precious friend!
その大切なシカマルは→
Around now, your precious friend
should be receiving Lord Gengo's will.
今頃 ゲンゴ様に
志をいただいているはずさ。
キミが
いくら命を張ったところでね。
Even as you lay your life on the line.
なんにも わかってないのね。
You don't understand, do you?
大切な仲間ってのはさ→
The precious friend I'm talking about…
is you!
あんたのことよ！
You belong to the Hidden Leaf.
((お前は 木ノ葉の一員だ。
それを忘れんな！))
Don't ever forget that!
友達ごっこなんて くだらないね。
Being friends is useless!
Then…
だったら
あんたの頬をつたっている→
Then what's that on your cheek?
それは何？
心転身の術！
Mind Transmission Jutsu!
しばらく あんたの精神を
乗っ取らせてもらうわ。
Let me take over your mind
for a little while.
(ゲンゴ)
貴君を ここへ誘い込んだのは→
I didn't lure you in here
just to prevent you from
using your shadows.
影を使わせないためだけではない。
視覚や嗅覚を奪われれば→
When a human loses
the ability to see and smell,
人間は
それだけ聴覚が鋭敏になる。
his sense of hearing
becomes much sharper.
ますます
てめえに有利ってわけか。
Giving you an even
greater advantage, huh?
(ゲンゴ)忍の世界には➡
In the shinobi world,
you're either the user or the used.
利用する人間と される人間の
どちらかしかいない。
何の話だ？
What're you talking about?
(ゲンゴ)
私が かつて信じた忍の言葉だよ。
Words from a shinobi that
I once believed in…
貴君も
桃地再不斬という名くらいは➡
Surely, even you've heard
the name Zabuza Momochi.
聞いたことがあるだろう。
Zabuza…
(シカマル)再不斬… たしか→
Wasn't he the instigator of
the Mizukage assassination incident?
水影暗殺事件を
起こしたとかっていう…。
(ゲンゴ)クーデター未遂ののち
私たちは里を抜けた。
After the failed coup d'état,
we deserted the village.
いつか舞い戻り
理想の社会を作るという→
We had faith in Zabuza's promise
to return some day to create
the ideal society.
再不斬の言葉を信じたのだ。
しかし 過酷な放浪は
彼を変えてしまった。
But the hardships of wandering
took its toll and changed him.
だから私は
逆に再不斬を利用したのさ。
And so, I used Zabuza instead.
彼の教えどおりにね。
Just as he had taught.
要は仲間を売ったって話だろ？
To put it bluntly,
you sold out your friend.
(ゲンゴ)そして 同志とともに
私は この地に移った。
And I settled here with
my comrades.
再不斬のなしえなかった
理想の社会を築くためにな。
In order to create the ideal society
that Zabuza could not.
今ようやく
思いが実現しようとしている。
And now, it's finally becoming a reality.
貴君も ともに
その瞬間を迎えたくないかね？
Don't you want to usher
in that moment with me?
ごめんだぜ。
No thanks!
The only society I'll sacrifice
my life to protect
俺が この身を捧げて守りたいのは
木ノ葉だ！
is the Hidden Leaf!
(ゲンゴ)お父上や恩師が
そうしたようにか？
The same way that your father
and mentor did?
軽々しく 親父やアスマのことを
口にするんじゃねえ！
You have no right to talk about
my dad or Asuma!
てめえの理想とやらは
俺が打ち砕いてやるぜ。
I'll tear down your ideals!
拙者は 何を…。
What has happened…to me?
おぬしは…。
You are…?
頭が ガンガンするし。
Like, my head is throbbing…
あとは あいつだけだな。
That's guy's…
the only one left.
((サイ 返事をして！ サイ！
Sai...answer me!
Sai!
サイ…。
キミは誰？
Who are you?
あんたの友達よ。
I'm your friend.
違う
僕の友達は この子たちだけだ。
No…
They are my only friends.
ゲンゴってやつに
そう思い込まされているだけよ！
That's just what that guy Gengo
made you believe!
来るな 向こうへ行け！
Don't come any closer! Go away!
一緒に帰ろう サイ。
Let's go back together, Sai.
(みんなが
あんたのことを待ってる))
Everyone is waiting for you.
サイ… サイ。
Sai… Sai!
いの？
Ino?
戻ったのね！
シカマルは？
You're back!
Where is Shikamaru?!
シカマルなら
ゲンゴってやつを追っていったわ。
Shikamaru went after that Gengo guy.
ダメだ！ 今すぐ シカマルに伝えなきゃ。
That's not good!
I have to let Shikamaru
know right away!
何があっても
振り向いちゃいけない！
No matter what happens…
He can't turn around!
(ゲンゴ)それほどまでに
木ノ葉が大事か？
Is the Hidden Leaf
that important to you?
Damned right it is!
あたりめえだ！
Then I'll let you in on something good…
(ゲンゴ)ならば もう一つ
いい話を聞かせよう。
私が この辺境の地にこもって
何もせず→
Do you think that I only isolated
myself in this region
and did nothing else?
座していただけだと思うかね？
もし 志を授けた同志たちを→
What would you think
if I've sent my initiates with
the will I bestowed upon them,
すでに 各国に
潜伏させているとしたら どうだ？
into all of the Hidden Villages?
The people of the Five Great Nations
aren't blind.
五大国の連中の目も節穴じゃねえ。
いくら中枢部に
もぐり込ませようが→
Your people may have
infiltrated the core,
but they'll get caught in time.
いずれは網に引っかかる。
I'm talking about the citizens…
(ゲンゴ)里の人々…
例えば キミのごく身近な人の→
The safety of those
who are most dear to you…
安全のことを言っているのだ。
なん… だと？
What did you say?
One signal from me,
and they will create an incident.
私の合図ひとつで
彼らはいつでも事を起こせる。
You don't have the means to stop it.
貴君にそれを止めるすべはない。
You're bluffing!
ブラフだ！
(ゲンゴ)ウソかまことかは 今にわかる。
In time, you'll see if I'm lying or not.
Stop!
Don't you dare touch Mirai!
(紅)やめろ ミライに手を出すな！
(ミライ)シカの兄ちゃ…。
(紅)ミライ ミライ！
Big Brother Shika!
Mirai!
ふ… 振り返ってたまるかよ。
Y-You can't fool me…
てめえが声にチャクラを流し込み→
I've already figured out that
you infuse chakra into your voice
人を操ろうとしてることは
お見通しなんだ！
to manipulate people.
(ゲンゴ)頭で振り返るまいと
すればするほど→
The more you resist with your mind,
the more the heart seeks it.
心は逆を求めるものだ。
クッ…。
(ミライ)シカの兄ちゃ…。
Big Brother Shika!
(紅)ミライ！
Mirai!
You'll pay if you lay
a hand on Mirai…
ミライに手を出しやがったら
承知しねえ。
そんときは てめえの息の根も
止めてやる！
I'll make sure your breath
is completely snuffed out.
Kill… Kill…
殺せ 殺せ…。
(シカマル)ゲンゴ てめえは危険だ。
生かしちゃおけねえ。
– Gengo, you're dangerous.
– Kill… Kill…
I can't let you go on living.
木ノ葉を守るためだ。
This is to protect the Hidden Leaf!
そのために
らしくねえ役目まで負って➡
– It's for that reason that...
– Kill… Kill…
I've come to carry out
a mission that's not like me!
俺は ここに来たんだ！
ナルトを 火影にするために！
– In order to make Naruto the Hokage!
– Kill… Kill…
ナルト。
Naruto…
(ナルト)ラーメン。
Ramen!
はぁ？ んだよ それ。
Huh?
What the hell was that?
(ゲンゴ)どうした シカマル？
What's the matter, Shikamaru?
さあ 己の心に巣食う闇と
向き合うのだ。
Now, confront the darkness
that consumes your heart!
フッ。
I-I have to get it right
the next time.
俺 次こそ完璧に
こなさなきゃいけないんだ。
あのな ガキなんだから
もうちょい気楽でいいんだよ。
Look, you're just a brat,
so it's okay if you ease up a little.
でも 俺のせいで仲間が…。
But it's my fault that my friends…
仲間を思う気持は大事だけどよ→
Thinking about your friends
is important.
そんなに全部を
しょい込むことはないんだぜ。
But you don't have to take on
all that responsibility.
めんどくせぇからよ。
'Cuz it's a drag.
Why?
なぜだ？ なぜ術にかからない？
Why doesn't my jutsu work on you?
貴様の心は
隙だらけではないか！
Your heart is full of cracks!
そうさ 俺の心は隙だらけ。
Yeah... My heart is full of cracks…
いや 隙しかねえんだ。
In fact, it's nothing but one big crack.
バ バカな！
I-Impossible!
Your words don't have
any effect on me anymore.
てめえの言葉は
もう俺には効かねえ！
I finally understand.
ようやくわかったぜ。
さっき同志と一緒に
この国に来たと言ったな？
Earlier, you said you came to
this land with your comrades.
だったら どうして
てめえの横には→
But why isn't there a single comrade
standing beside you?
誰ひとり いねえんだろうな？
You probably killed them all,
and hid them in this castle, right?
そいつら全部葬っちまって
この城に隠したんだろ？
他人を利用するか されるかでしか
考えられねえ てめえは孤独だ！
You're all alone,
because you only believe in
using others or being used.
ここは まるで てめえの心の奥を
のぞき見てるようだぜ。
This place is like peering deep
into your heart!
貴様と私は似ている！
You and I are alike!
頭がキレるせいで
他人を信用できない。
We're smart, we can't trust anyone!
一緒にすんじゃねえ！
Don't lump me in with you!
貴様ら！
You—!
まだ 正気のようだな。
Looks like you're still conscious!
あぁ。 ちょっと危なかったけどな。
Yeah, but it was touch and
go for a little while.
(シカマル)朧！ 鏃！
Ro, Soku!
いくぞ。
Let's go.
よし！ さっさと片づけちゃおう。
Okay, let's clean this up quickly!
Why don't we leave it
to them this time?
今回は
あいつらに任せてみないか？
そっか…
シカマルが認めた２人だもんね。
Yeah, you're right…
Shikamaru did just call
on those two.
はぁ～っ！
分身か！
A clone?!
That's right. With his chakra—!
確かに やつのチャクラを…。
影に チャクラをまとわせるだと!?
どれが 実体だ？
Enveloping his shadow
with chakra?!
Which one is real?
体が… 動かん！
I can't...move!
私を止めれば
忍の世界は 必ず 衰退する！
If you stop me,
the world of the shinobi will decline!
大名に奉仕するだけの
卑しい存在に落ちぶれても→
Don't you care
if you're consigned
to a life of servitude under
the Feudal Lords?
かまわぬと いうのか!?
A place where even the easygoing
can live in their own way…
ぼんやり生きたいやつらでも
それなりに生きていける…。
俺が守りたいのは
そんな世の中だ！
That's the kind of world
I want to protect!
How stupid!
くだらぬ！
I will not let you interfere
with my vision!
貴様らのような下賎な者どもに➡
私の理想を邪魔されてたまるか！
舌に流れるチャクラを断ったし。
Like, the chakra flowing to
your tongue's been cut off…
うぅ…。
任務… 完了だ。
Mission…complete!
ご苦労だった。
Good work.
We'll be taking Gengo
and his revolutionaries
これから
ゲンゴ および かく者たちを➡
木ノ葉の里に連行するが→
back to the Hidden Leaf Village now.
お前たちも一緒に来るか？
Will you be joining us?
拙者たちは…。
We…
(シカマル)また助けられちまったな…。
You came to the rescue again.
ったく…
お前は たいしたやつだぜ ナルト。
Sheesh...
You really are something, Naruto.
(シカマル)お前ら…。
You guys!
なんだ？ 忘れ物か？
What? Did you forget something?
(鏃)里に帰るまでが任務だって
言われたし。
Like, we were told
we're on a mission
until we get back to the village.
(朧)シカマル殿にお供するでござるよ。
We shall accompany you,
Lord Shikamaru.
ん？ あぁ そうか。
Huh? Oh, yeah?
(ユリト)先輩！
Senpai!
(シカマル)ユリト!?
Yurito?!
お前… 来てたのか。
You came too?
(ユリト)俺も やっと でかい案件
任されるようになったっすよ。
I finally got to handle
a big assignment!
(シカマル)えっ？ お… おう。
O-Oh…
Huh? Senpai, aren't you being
too stiff and formal again?
あれ～？ 先輩 また
力みすぎてるんじゃないっすか？
雲 雲！ 雲っすよ。
Clouds! The clouds!
Remember, the clouds!
あ… あぁ。
Oh, yeah…
そんじゃ 俺 忙しいんで。
失礼しま～す。
Anyways, I'm busy,
so 'scuse me!
ハハハ…。
シカマル殿？
Lord Shikamaru?
雲ってのは
掴もうとしても掴めねえ。
You can reach out to try
and grab the cloud…
but you can never grasp it.
風があれば 吹き飛んじまう。
If there's wind, it'll blow away.
芯のねえ 胡乱なもんだな。
Such a strange thing with no core.
(シカマル)テマリ。
ん？ なんだ？
Temari…
Huh? What is it?
別に その…
なんでもねえけどよ あの…。
Well… It's nothing important, but…
Um…
なんだ？ はっきり言え。
What is it?
Spit it out.
お前の平手打ち
ちっとは加減しろよな。
Go a bit easier
when you slap people, will you?
また ボサッとしてたら
何度でも張り倒してやるぞ。
If you space out again,
I'll slap you as much as I want to!
じゃ… じゃあ 次も頼むぜ。
Okay… I'm counting on you for that.
ん？
(シカマル)今回は… ありがとな。
Thanks…for what you did this time.
(いの)キィーッ！ なんつう
ぶったるい会話してんの!?
Is this an awkward conversation
or what?!
デートくらい チャッチャと誘いなさいよ！
まぁ まぁ！
Just hurry and ask her on a date!
There, there…
(サイ)いの。
(いの)サイ？
Ino…
Sai?
ありがとう 美人さん。
Thanks, beautiful.
感じたよ キミの優しさ。
I really felt…your kindness.
美人!? そ… そんな…。
Beautiful? Oh…uh!
何か お礼がしたいな。
キミさえよければ だけど。
I want to thank you…
That's if you'd let me.
だ だ… だったら あの…
デ デ デ… デートなど…。
Oh… Well then…
Maybe a d-date…?
いの… ぶったるくなってるよ。
Ino, now you're being awkward.
今度 その… なんだ…
飯でも一緒にどうだ？
Maybe…next time…we can…
go get a bite to eat.
デートか？
はぁ!?
You mean, a date?
Huh?
それは デートの誘いなのか？
Are you asking me out on a date?
ま… まぁな。
Well, yeah.
そうか デートか。
I see. A date, huh.
嫌なのかよ？
You don't want to?
そうではないが…。
えっ!? ん？
That's not it.
Huh? Uh?
覚悟しろ。
私とのデートは面倒だぞ。
Be prepared.
A date with me
can be quite a drag.
作戦はあるのでござろうな？
はぁ!?
Do you have a plan?
Huh?
デートの作戦だし。
んなもん ねえよ！
Like, a date strategy.
Like I'd have one!
作戦なしの初デートなんて➡
Going on a first date
without a strategy
素手で 尾獣と
戦うようなもんだし。
is like fighting
a Tailed Beast unarmed.
勝ち目は皆無でござるな。
You have zero chance of winning.
お前らに何がわかるんだよ!?
What would you two know?!
何を隠そう 拙者 恋愛事情には
少々 うるそうござる。
What are you saying?!
I do know a thing or two
about relationships.
まずは テマリ殿の好みを
徹底的に調べたうえで→
You must first find out
everything you can
入念なプランを練るでござる。
それも 晴れの日 曇り 雨の
３パターンは 最低でも必要だし！
相手を退屈させない小話も→
シチュエーションに応じて 100個ほど
ストックしておくべきでござろうな。
おい おい…。
それって
ゲンゴを倒すより めんどくせぇ。